# Bruno Alejandro Bahamondes Pérez

### **Personal Information**

o Address: Providencia, Santiago, Región Metropolitana, Chile.

Phone Number: +56 9 9199 9324Email: bahamondesbp@gmail.com

o Rut: 19.208.517-9

O Date of birth: 22/01/1996

O Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bbahamondes/

## Summary

Bilingual Informatics Engineer with over five years of experience in the area. I'm experienced in managing Hadoop environments, troubleshooting JVM issues, configuration and network issues. I'm familiar with both Hortonworks and Cloudera environments with varying degrees of expertise in the Hadoop components. I'm also experienced in scripting, mostly self taught on Bash and Python.

# **Work History**

Cloudera Chile

<sup>O</sup> Staff Customer Operations Engineer

2019–Present

Bilingual Technical Support for Data in motion services like YARN, Spark, Kafka, Apache NiFi, NiFi Registry and MiNiFi. Subject Matter Expert in NiFi.

Hortonworks Chile

' Associate Technical Support Engineer

2018-2019

Gave bilingual technical support for Hadoop services including HDFS, Zookeeper, YARN, etc; managing customer expectations and critical situations.

Bprog LTDA Chile

Software Developer

2017-2018

Solved difficult problems and designed solutions tailored to the customer's requirements. Worked under pressure to meet deadlines.

### Qualifications

0	Certified Kubernetes Admin Linux Foundation, LF-odfs7zdngg	<b>Chile</b> 2020–2023
0	Ingenieria Informatica Instituto Profesional DuocUC	<b>Chile</b> 2019–2021
0	Analista Programador Computacional Instituto Profesional DuocUC	<b>Chile</b> 2015–2017

#### Skills

#### O Hadoop Ecosystem

HDFS, MapReduce, YARN, Apache NiFi, MiNiFi, Hive, Kafka, Zookeeper, Spark, Kerberos, JVM Troubleshooting.

Languages

Fluent English. Native Spanish

O Programming Languages

Advanced knowledge on: C#, Python. Intermediate on: Java.

O Database Languages

SQL, PL/SQL, Transact-SQL.

○ **Web Development Languages**Advanced knowledge on: PHP, Django, Jquery, JavaScript, LATEX.